well hello everyone this is Frankie
Freitas welcome back to another week of
Holo talk for the week of January 9th
2000 it's almost getting ready to say 19
something but it's 2 000 now we're back
brand new year brand new century some
people would argue it's a new millennium
some people would argue it's not but we
won't even get into that
um we have a guest this week ikuo
Nakamura who is a holographic artist
that is working out of his studio in
Brooklyn New York those beautiful
beautiful a white light transmission
work and while you listen to the
interview you may want to click on the
link to his website either during the
interview or after you finish enjoying
the interview and see some of the
beautiful beautiful uh work that he's
done in the field of holography so uh
that interview's coming up in just a few
minutes first there's not a lot new
that's happened over the holidays uh
since you know we spoke last and broke
from I broke for the holiday break
at the website I have something new that
I'm going to run each week and that's a
laser and holography poll and where you
can log on each week and voice your
opinion on different topics and
different subjects and related to the
fields of lasers and holography and last
week the first question was up and it
did went up late in the week it went up
on Thursday so I only have three days
results from that but I do have some
results and I'd like to share those
results with you the question was
and when do you think holographic
television will become a reality and
here's the uh the results of that poll
five percent of the respondents to the
poll said that they thought that
holographic television would become a
reality within one year 42 which was the
highest percent of all the questions and
all the responses uh 42 percent said
that holographic TV would be a reality
within five years thirty percent said
ten years 16 said that it would take 20
years or more before we would be
enjoying a holographic television and
surprisingly six percent of the
respondents said that we would never
see holographic television so a very
interesting little result there to that
first survey uh Paul holography poll
that we had up and each Sunday a new
question will go up and you come onto
the website and voice your opinion and
have your vote tabulated
question this week is should schools
offer laser and holography programs to
the students
and the way that you can answer that is
yes at the elementary level yes at the
middle school level yes at the high
school level or no schools should not
offer these programs at all so uh go
back to the home page if you haven't
been there already and please take the
laser holography poll and I may be able
to take a copy of that and put that
right on the whole talk page so as you
come on to listen to the show each week
the poll will be right there for you and
you can continuously update that and see
what the total of the responses are as
the week goes on so something fun to do
something different you know gotta Gotta
Have Some Fun well let's move on to our
interview I do have a number of people
who are scheduled to come on the show
for the next uh quite a few weeks
actually as we go through the deep dark
cold winter that's coming up so what
better way to sit back and enjoy these
uh Bleak months than to
sit back and listen to a show of
holotalk well let me get this call hold
on a second
okay I'm back sorry I usually turn the
ringer off when I'm doing the show and I
forgot to do it this time so I guess I'm
a little rusty from having so much time
off during the holidays so yes like I
was saying we have a lot of guests
coming up that come back each week and
hear a new guest and uh
let's move on to our interview with ikuo
Nakamura and don't forget to visit his
website and see some of the beautiful
work in holography that he's doing and
thanks to everyone I also want to throw
this in quickly thanks to everyone who
sent all those Hall talk shows that I
had lost right before the holiday season
was over unfortunately
unfortunate number of shows that I had
done ahead of time which never had been
posted yet which I have to redo but the
ones that were finished
I now have them oh this is crazy can you
believe this for a Sunday hold on
okay I'm back I'm not even going to
chance that phone ring again I thought
I'd turned the ringer off again and
apparently there's something crazy with
the phone because it's telling me that
the Ringer's off
just go to the show all right here's our
interview thanks for tuning in don't
forget tune in every week we've got a
lot of great shows coming up of course
that's for you to decide whether they're
great or not but
I'll do them and you decide okay see you
later this is Frankie Freitas for whole
talk
hello this is Frank defreitis and I'm
speaking to ikuo makanur how are you
today oh very good okay thanks for
coming into the studio is it last week
or the week before yeah
right yeah yeah yeah
why don't we start out this week's
Interview With You by uh telling the
hollow talk listeners about how you got
started in holography and when you got
started in holography
oh yes
um actually I'm Japanese I started
Photography in Japan actually I learned
in Japan
um I studied physics science in Japan
and where I learned at the park of iron
so but it's still impressive even you
know I study like a custom area or
Nuclear Physics but uh program is more
mysterious
and where I saw
foreign
[Music]
because of who influenced you so early
on in holography are they the reason why
you've chosen white light transmission
holography to work in opposed to
reflection holography
but true because you know in New York uh
just accordingly
yeah or you know that's equipment
I learned from them
um you know I I could visit them so I
have a chance to see how they have to
remake program
no but especially you know about me
choreography is not only 3D photography
yeah
um
rainbow hologram with like more light
character yes so I really like work with
light yeah very mad so you know
sometimes rainbow program people think
it's very you know artificial light for
but for me
that's why I like rainbow program very
much yeah I I think it lends itself more
to and of course people would argue this
but personally I feel it lends itself
more to artistic expression uh than
reflection holography oh well you know I
like regretting all of them too of
course but I accused you know rainbow
program and uh
contacting light yeah play with rainbow
colors now you've done some pulsed Ruby
work and a number of pieces that laser
transmission as well oh yes recently you
know I get some really proud and in
terms of holographic uh in New York City
and uh yeah I have a tattoo it will be
the optic related program yeah so yeah
that was wonderful yeah you know laser
transmission Holograms are actually my
favorite oh yeah always have been and
always will be what do you think is the
drawback that we do not see more of them
is is it the the fact that it's so
expensive to re-illuminate them during
an exhibit I mean if you if you've shot
10 laser transmission Holograms you're
going to need quite a few lasers to
illuminate them is is it the cost of the
of exhibiting them that we don't see
them as much uh yeah I I guess you know
because you know since the invention of
white light truck with the Hologram or
reflection program I think choreographer
tried to make hologram by Illuminating
by I mean I would like yeah and uh most
of us keep up I'll forget about
it but I think most of us still love
them you know
program eliminated by later yeah it's
the most exciting oh yeah I love it my
heart just pounds faster when I see a
laser transmission hologram it's a shame
the public it doesn't have the
opportunity to see more of them but
actually you know I I just told you
about I have a constitute will be about
I will show that speech by later okay
yeah so I'm ready
tell us a little bit about your studio
you have your own private Studio that
you work from right and is it in
Brooklyn oh yes yeah tell us a little
bit about that well actually I used to
have my studio in
close to Times Square it's just one girl
from you know the famous Millennium
countdown right yeah
you have the studio there but I moved to
Brooklyn and I built very long table
36 foot table
thank you
yeah you know I
I really satisfied about that because I
have two major benefits one is um
actually I got other bites from dark
spots and submarine because if we have
enough distance from special character
to him no the pain will be very close to
automated yes so I didn't have you know
in coordinated
so I think it's very clear image
and the second is actually you know I
got idea from Rudy bhagwan so he's doing
also
um I can split uh too bad from one table
oh I see so you can shoot your Masters
and do your transfer copying
without taking your setup or putting it
up or taking it down oh yeah I can keep
uh he's expecting yeah and copy yeah
that's nice yeah
yeah
what are some of your most recent pieces
that you've worked on uh I understand a
few of them are not conventional type of
uh what we consider conventional
holographic work like the newer whole
gram in the mirror what about some of
those pieces oh yes
um
actually interact with your brain weight
video
the brainwave if I sat there maybe
something wouldn't happen at all well
actually yeah that's just a joke sorry
okay yeah some people you know
everybody's different brainwave right
and when wave is just you know noise
from brain right so we cannot pick up
anything
so yeah so this is kind of
um maybe you most people know about very
famous hypothesis by
prelim and Paul oh yeah yeah the brain
yes exactly so this is kind of you know
metaphor
um okay communicate them between your
brain and the Hologram yeah the brain
um what about the mirror well Mira you
know it's also communication piece you
know so like a new hologram
um you know when you face to tell the
installation you can think about your
eating with your past or your memory and
you try to find out what happened in
holography and
name
um
I can say
it's about the time okay you can see
your own path
um actually a video he made let's see
so you image
it protected by a joy I see elements
so well
so essentially what you're doing in the
present turns around and affects your
past oh yeah correct which is actually a
mirror image of how Tom looks itself
yeah because what you do in the present
usually affects your future not your
past yes but uh you know we cannot
change password yes but I was thinking
about memory a lot actually in my memory
path right but uh and our own memory
always different every people have a
different memory yeah you know even but
you know you can then I think most
people tend your memory
now in real time very interesting yeah
yeah and we will have uh just to let the
listeners know there's a link to the
hololab website right on the whole talk
page so uh either while you're listening
to this show or shortly thereafter
listening to the show you can click on
that link and go to the website and see
the works that we're speaking about
right now
do you have any upcoming shows oh yes uh
well actually now I'm showing some video
production installation at the
um Museum of Art Ohio Okay so until end
of February so it's a title is video
into 21st century okay
I think it's very wonderful so
um
you know many other people from you know
Europe and Japan and they're going over
there and also
actually thanks to share Water
Foundation
um you know
we have a artistic residence program in
hollow center and
you know we are going to work
um
from next uh Mark March
Dean Hardy and myself
until then next month I'll get in
Florida and equally to a Museum of
Contemporary Art Arizona okay yeah so
that my connection
so I will tell the laser eliminated
program and I'll make sure that I get an
announcement out to everyone when those
shows are going to get ready to open so
if you want to just send me an email and
let me know that you know maybe two
weeks ahead of time we'll make an
announcement and make sure that everyone
knows that those events are coming up oh
yeah yeah
okay
anything else you want to let us know
about before we close out the
no not actually no I really enjoyed I
visited your video and uh it was a lot
of fun having you here oh yes and uh
diode later
yeah yeah that's nice I would like to
see the news you know four illuminations
so that people would be able to see more
laser transmission Holograms you know a
lot less expensive than going out and
purchasing the equivalent gas laser to
do that yeah yeah
well thank you very much for being on
the show and stay in touch I'll be in
touch with you because I know you took
one of the uh the lasers back with you
so we'll have to follow up and see how
that's going for you and I'll be coming
in for your New York opening oh yeah in
March and I'd like to
suggest that everyone head over to the
websites that are listed on the whole
talk page and take a look at all the
beautiful beautiful work that eqo has
has done over the years spanning how
many years now well
yeah yeah
I don't know yeah yeah yeah
okay well you take care and and thank
you very much for uh coming on the show
all right thank you all right I'll talk
to you soon okay